Privacy Policy
==============

**Simply Earth Privacy Policy.**

**Last updated: 23/03/2024**

This Privacy Policy describes how Simply Earth (the "**_Site_**", "**_we_**", "**_us_**", **_or_** "**_our_**") collects, uses, and discloses your personal information when you visit, use our services, or make a purchase from https://simplyearth.com/ (the "**_Site_**") or otherwise communicate with us (collectively, the "Services"). For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "**_you_**" and **_"your_**" means you as the user of the Services, whether you are a customer, website visitor, or another individual whose information we have collected under this Privacy Policy.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By using and accessing any Services, you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use or access any of the Services.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, including to reflect changes to our practices or for other operational, legal, or regulatory reasons. We will post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site, update the "**Last updated**" date, and take any other steps required by applicable law.

**How We Collect and Use Your Personal Information**

To provide the Services, we collect and have collected over the past 12 months personal information about you from a variety of sources, as set out below. The information that we collect and use varies depending on how you interact with us.

In addition to the specific uses set out below, we may use the information we collect about you to communicate with you, provide the Services, comply with any applicable legal obligations, enforce any applicable terms of service, and protect or defend the Services, our rights, and the rights of our users or others.

**What Personal Information We Collect**

The types of personal information we obtain about you depend on how you interact with our Site and use our Services. When we use the term "**_personal information_**", we are referring to information that identifies, relates to, describes, or can be associated with you. The following sections describe the categories and specific types of personal information we collect.

**Information We Collect Directly from You**

Information that you directly submit to us through our Services may include:

\- Basic contact details including your name, address, phone number, and email.

\- Order information including your name, billing address, shipping address, payment confirmation, email address, and phone number.

\- Account information including your username, password, and security questions.

\- Shopping information including the items you view, put in your cart, or add to your wishlist.

\- Customer support information including the information you choose to include in communications with us, for example, when sending a message through the Services.

Some features of the Services may require you to directly provide us with certain information about yourself. You may elect not to provide this information, but doing so may prevent you from using or accessing these features.

**Information We Collect Through Cookies**

We also automatically collect certain information about your interaction with the Services ("**_Usage Data_**"). To do this, we may use cookies, pixels, and similar technologies ("**_Cookies_**"). Usage Data may include information about how you access and use our Site and your account, including device information, browser information, information about your network connection, your IP address, and other information regarding your interaction with the Services.

**Information We Obtain from Third Parties**

Finally, we may obtain information about you from third parties, including vendors and service providers who may collect information on our behalf, such as:

\- Companies who support our Site and Services

\- Our payment processors, who collect payment information (e.g., bank account, credit or debit card information, billing address) to process your payment to fulfill your orders and provide you with products or services you have requested, to perform our contract with you.

\- When you visit our Site, open or click on emails we send you, or interact with our Services or advertisements, we, or third parties we work with, may automatically collect certain information using online tracking technologies such as pixels, web beacons, software developer kits, third-party libraries, and cookies.

Any information we obtain from third parties will be treated under this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible or liable for the accuracy of the information provided to us by third parties and are not responsible for any third party's policies or practices. For more information, see the section below, Third Party Websites and Links.

**How We Use Your Personal Information**

\- Providing Products and Services. We use your personal information to provide you with the Services to perform our contract with you, including processing your payments, fulfilling your orders, sending notifications to your related account, purchases, returns, exchanges, or other transactions, creating, maintaining, and otherwise managing your account, arranging for shipping, facilitating any returns and exchanges and to enable you to post reviews.

\- Marketing and Advertising. We use your personal information for marketing and promotional purposes, such as to send marketing, advertising and promotional communications by email, text message, or postal mail, and to show you advertisements for products or services.

This may include using your personal information to better tailor the Services and advertising on our Site and other websites.

\- Security and Fraud Prevention. We use your personal information to detect, investigate, or take action regarding possible fraudulent, illegal, or malicious activity. If you choose to use the Services and register an account, you are responsible for keeping your account credentials safe. We highly recommend that you do not share your username, password, or other access details with anyone else. If you believe your account has been compromised, please contact us immediately.

\- Communicating with you. We use your personal information to provide you with customer support and improve our Services. This is in our legitimate interests to be responsive to you, to provide effective services to you, and to maintain our business relationship with you.

**Cookies**

Like many websites, we use Cookies on our Site. For specific information about the Cookies that we use related to powering our store.

We use Cookies to power and improve our Site and our Services (including to remember your actions and preferences), to run analytics and better understand user interaction with the Services (in our legitimate interests to administer, improve, and optimize the Services). We may also permit third parties and service providers to use Cookies on our Site to better tailor the services, products, and advertising on our Site and other websites.

**You have control over how cookies are used on this website. Here's how to manage your cookie preferences in your browser settings.**

**Be aware:** Changing your cookie settings might affect your experience on this website. Some features or functionalities might not work as intended, or you might see less relevant content.

**It's important to note:** Adjusting your cookie preferences won't completely prevent information sharing with third parties, such as our advertising partners.

**How We Disclose Personal Information**

In certain circumstances, we may disclose your personal information to third parties for legitimate purposes subject to this Privacy Policy.

Such circumstances may include:

\- With vendors or other third parties who perform services on our behalf (e.g., IT management, payment processing, data analytics, customer support, cloud storage, fulfillment, and shipping).

\- With business and marketing partners, to provide services and advertise to you. 

Our business and marketing partners will use your information in accordance with their own privacy notices.

\- When you direct, request us or otherwise consent to our disclosure of certain information to third parties, such as to ship your products or through your use of social media widgets or login integrations, with your consent.

\- With our affiliates or otherwise within our corporate group, in our legitimate interests to run a successful business.

\- In connection with a business transaction such as a merger or bankruptcy, to comply with any applicable legal obligations (including to respond to subpoenas, search warrants, and similar requests), to enforce any applicable terms of service, and to protect or defend the Services, our rights, and the rights of our users or others.

We have, in the past 12 months disclosed the following categories of personal information and sensitive personal information (denoted by \*) about users for the purposes set out above in "How We Collect and Use Your Personal Information" and "How We Disclose Personal about users for the purposes set out above in "How We Collect and Use Your Personal Information" and "How We Disclose Personal Information":

**Category:**

\- Identifiers such as basic contact details and certain order and account information

\- Commercial information such as order information, shopping information, and customer support information

\- Internet or other similar network activity, such as Usage Data

**Categories of Recipients:**

\- Vendors and third parties who perform services on our behalf (such as Internet service providers, payment processors, fulfillment partners, customer support partners and data analytics providers)

\- Business and marketing partners

\- Affiliates

We do not use or disclose sensitive personal information for inferring characteristics about you.

We have "sold" and "shared" (as those terms are defined in applicable law) personal information over the preceding 12 months for the purpose of engaging in advertising and marketing activities, as follows.

**Category of Personal Information**

\- Identifiers such as basic contact details and certain order and account information

\- Commercial information such as records of products or services purchased and shopping information

\- Internet or other similar network activity, such as Usage Data

**Categories of Recipients**

\- Business and marketing partners

**User Generated Content**

The Services may enable you to post product reviews and other user-generated content. If you choose to submit user-generated content to any public area of the Services, this content will be public and accessible by anyone.

We do not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make available to others and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such information will respect your privacy or keep it secure. We are not responsible for the privacy or security of any information that you make publicly available, or for the accuracy, use, or misuse of any information that you disclose or receive from third parties.

**Third-Party Websites and Links**

Our Site may provide links to websites or other online platforms operated by third parties. If you follow links to sites not affiliated or controlled by us, you should review their privacy and security policies and other terms and conditions. We do not guarantee and are not responsible for the privacy or security of such sites, including the accuracy, completeness, or reliability of information found on these sites. Information you provide on public or semi-public venues, including information you share on third-party social networking platforms may also be viewable by other users of the Services and/or users of those third-party platforms without limitation as to its use by us or by a third party. Our inclusion of such links does not, by itself, imply any endorsement of the content on such platforms or of their owners or operators, except as disclosed on the Services.

**Children's Data**

The Services are not intended to be used by children, and we do not knowingly collect any personal information about children. If you are the parent or guardian of a child who has provided us with their personal information, you may contact us using the contact details set out below to request that it be deleted.

As of the Effective Date of this Privacy Policy, we do not have actual knowledge that we "share" or "sell" (as those terms are defined in applicable law) personal information of individuals under 16 years of age.

**Security and Retention of Your Information**

Please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable, and we cannot guarantee "perfect security." In addition, any information you send to us may not be secure while in transit. We recommend that you do not use unsecured channels to communicate sensitive or confidential information to us.

How long we retain your personal information depends on different factors, such as whether we need the information to maintain your account, to provide the Services, comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce other applicable contracts and policies.

**Your Rights and Choices**

Depending on where you live, you may have some or all of the rights listed below about your personal information. However, these rights are not absolute, may apply only in certain circumstances, and, in certain cases, we may decline your request as permitted by law.

\- Right to Access / Know. You may have a right to request access to personal information that we hold about you, including details relating to how we use and share your information.

\- Right to Delete. You may have a right to request that we delete the personal information we maintain about you.

\- Right to Correct. You may have a right to request that we correct the inaccurate personal information we maintain about you.

\- Right of Portability. You may have a right to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to request that we transfer it to a third party, in certain circumstances, and with certain exceptions.

\- Right to Opt out of Sale or Sharing or Targeted Advertising. You may have a right to direct us not to "sell" or "share" your personal information or to opt out of the processing of your personal information for purposes considered to be "targeted advertising", as defined in applicable privacy laws. Please note that if you visit our Site with the Global Privacy Control opt-out preference signal enabled, depending on where you are, we will automatically treat this as a request to opt out of the "sale" or "sharing" of information for the device and browser that you used to visit the Site.

\- Right to Limit and/or Opt out of Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information. You may have a right to direct us to limit our use and/or disclosure of sensitive personal information to only what is necessary to perform the Services or provide the goods reasonably expected by an average individual.

\- Restriction of Processing: You may have the right to ask us to stop or restrict our processing of personal information.

\- Withdrawal of Consent: Where we rely on consent to process your personal information, you may have the right to withdraw this consent.

\- Appeal: You may have a right to appeal our decision if we decline to process your request. You can do so by replying directly to our denial.

\- Managing Communication Preferences: We may send you promotional emails, and you may opt out of receiving these at any time by using the unsubscribe option displayed in our emails to you. If you opt-out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as those about your account or orders that you have made.

You may exercise any of these rights where indicated on our Site or by contacting us using the contact details provided below.

We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of these rights. We may need to collect information from you to verify your identity, such as your email address or account information, before providing a substantive response to the request. By applicable laws, You may designate an authorized agent to make requests on your behalf to exercise your rights. Before accepting such a request from an agent, we will require that the agent provide proof you have authorized them to act on your behalf, and we may need you to verify your identity directly with us. We will respond to your request promptly as required under applicable law.

* 
* 
* 

Call us at [866-330-8165](tel:866-330-8165) or [\[email protected\]](https://simplyearth.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Monday - Friday 7-3 CST

© Copyright Simply Earth. All rights reserved.

### About

### Help

Questions? Chat With Us!

Close
